

# **Summary**

A self-driven engineering graduate with a track record of rigorous problem-solving and 2+ years of consistent programming. I enjoy working across the stacks and preach teamwork and testing for agile software development. With prior experiences in consulting, research, and entrepreneurship, I care deeply about delivering functional and intuitive products to clients and users.

# **Projects**

Cryptofolio Mar. 2021

Tech Stack: JavaScript, React, Chart.js, Material-UI, Sass, Express, ElephantSQL

- Built a responsive portfolio single page application with intuitive and custom data visualizations
- $\bullet \ \mathsf{Designed} \ \mathsf{relational} \ \mathsf{database} \ \mathsf{tables} \ \& \ \mathsf{REST} \ \mathsf{API} \ \mathsf{endpoints} \ \mathsf{and} \ \mathsf{utilized} \ \mathsf{public} \ \mathsf{APIs} \ \mathsf{to} \ \mathsf{consume} \ \mathsf{data}$

Scheduler Feb. 2021

Tech Stack: JavaScript, Storybook, React, Express, Postgres, Jest, Cypress, CircleCI

- Implemented WebSockets and reducers for facilitating real-time interview appointments
- Adopted CI/CD and test-driven development by writing unit, integration, and E2E tests

Jungle Mar. 2021

Tech Stack: Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, Postgres, RSpec, Capybara, PhantomJS

Developed new product features, feature tests, and user authentication for an Amazon clone

Crawler June 2020

Tech Stack: C, Valgrind, libcurl

• Created an asynchronous and multithreaded crawler for downloading PNG files

# **Employment**

## Simpson Gumpertz & Heger

Consulting Intern

San Francisco, US Sept. 2019 to Dec. 2019

- Evaluated design alternatives based on engineering physics and best practices
- · Collaborated with project managers for providing proposals and recommendations to clients
- $\bullet \ \text{Created visualizations to simplify the design process by parsing design codes and standards } \\$

### Water Institute - University of Waterloo

Research Developer

Waterloo, CA May 2018 to Aug. 2018

- Measured model's forecasting accuracy by analysing time-series output through R's dynamic time warping package
- $\bullet \ \, \text{Analysed and tested interflow and infiltration algorithms for a computational hydrology model } \\$
- Presented research summary at the Canadian Geophysical Union Conference to researchers

EllisDon Project Coordinator Ottawa, CA Sept. 2017 to Dec. 2017

• Conducted QA inspections, cost estimation, project planning & scheduling in a 200+ people team

 Acted as a liaison among subcontractors and project managers by identifying and reporting outstanding issues

## **Awards**

CS50 Al Certificate

Dec. 2020

• Completed 12 AI projects and 7 quizzes including optimizations, neural networks, and ML

### Hult Prize Waterloo Finalist - For Us, By Us

Nov. 2018

• Pitched and mocked a handicraft e-commerce platform to empower young women in developing countries by creating employment opportunities and connecting them with global consumers

### **UW Warriors Varsity Tennis**

Fall 2018

• Trained and competed in provincial season playoff as a top 4 team while completing full-time study

## **Contact**

**▼** sjtan@uwaterloo.ca

in dan-tan-7b5a89109/

C dantan0

## **Skills**

#### **LANGUAGES**

Python

SQL

**JavaScript** 

TypeScript

Ruby

HTML5

Sass

C/C++

#### FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES

React

Redux

jQuery

Bootstrap

Express Rails

Jest

-

Cypress

TensorFlow

#### **TOOLS**

Git

Docker

CircleCl

Heroku

Unity

**Figma** 

#### DATABASES

**Postgres** 

MongoDB

## **Education**

### **Lighthouse Labs**

Mar. 202<sup>1</sup>

Diploma, Full-Stack Web Development

## University of Waterloo 2015 to 2020

Bachelor of Applied Science, Civil Eng. CS: Algorithms & Data Structures, Systems Programming & Concurrency, Databases & Software Design, Pattern Recognition

### University of Leeds Jan. 2019 to June 2019

 Conducted numerical computation of heat and fluid flow in microchannels using MATLAB and Ansys